a couple of times and unfortunately my side was
empty and uh I was talking a little bit more than
usual in a way that I I was able to to to get
it back but now now I know it works okay so we
said that the make client now is able to tell
I'm a client make a client for this server and
what we pass is a label saying uh the name of
the server uh we are building for uh yeah and
the primary use case for that is in tests so in
a test the normal thing is just make a client for
the first server um and in the test environment
that's uh server running on the the first Port of
the um of the uh test setup and then to access
the other um servers running in the test setup
you can make client for the second server or
the third server and this is this is all very
simple it just um focuses on the server ID
that you've given it yes and when when you
match on that server ID it returns a client that's
specifically for that single host and this I can
show you one other thing at the top of the test
here which is how the test setup Works which is
that the default test setup has these three
servers those servers are now on these port
numbers yes this is a relatively new change
um it's a very new change okay and um these
these should not interfere with anything
else else um so when you're running tests
it it can listen on these ports I with good
reliability I want these changes I'm going to
pull your branch I'm going to to to basically
rebase or or on your branch because uh if the
change you should already have this if you
had my Branch from this weekend from last
weekend yeah I do have it uh let me
just you have it uh just need to find
it trck yes I have I do yeah so then uh anywhere
that you want to um do a test scenario you can
make a client for each different server and
then do things like we see here um tell one
client to um create a channel and then look
with another client and maybe you say second
in that case okay and with that other client
you'd look for the presence of that channel
if that doesn't happen right then the
replication of Channel creation is not
working okay so you can use these targeted client
objects for um functional testing of the expected
behavior of replicating between the different
servers and uh let me show you just
one other thing connected to that story
which is that um when we do set up these
different hosts yes uh it may be useful to
see a detail of how it does it so during
test setup it iterates through the hosts
and calls create server yes and this
third arent to create server is a
number okay go backward here I actually had
exactly a problem with this the server DB
that it was telling me I I don't have a
server DB please go ahead so um we have
this integer starts the first time we
hit here it starts at one and then when
we create that server on server DB
number one it should call through to
here
and that red sdb number is used
here and the way that works is by passing
that um database number into the redest
options I I did not understand why the
database is a number and what are the
implications if I need to know uh otherwise
um it's it's pretty simple um the you're
familiar with like a traditional database
you install postgress or you install my SQ
and you say create database project one yeah and
then create table one 2 three you got three tables
in your database switch databases project two
show tables no tables create table 3 four five
hey now you have um tables in each database the
database number in Rus is just the same idea it's
just that there are different database numbers and
not database names okay so database zero is the
default but as you can see in the code that we've
been reviewing um in the test environment it sets
database 1 two and three for Server first second
and third and there is no d B zero in the test
environment okay so basically new this number
go straight to reddish which uses number instead
of names for creating a database under the dbms
which is you know the redish stuff I get it yeah
yeah and to demonstrate that uh let me switch uh
uh sorry you get a blank screen there let me fix
that has it been sharing my screen yes I can see
your screen I see now your terminal couple of
terminals sorry um like have you been seeing the
code yes so far yes okay you have been seeing the
code good all right so what I need to do is make
sure this is always on the visible workspace and
then take my code and put it the other screen
okay so this terminal is what I wanted to um
have on screen for you all right so I what I was
trying to do is show you oh yes um if we run tests
normally it just runs the tests and you can see
hey it did a reset of redus and you know all
the log messages and we covered this the other
day but I figured it's good for the recording
you can say redus monitor equals one with the
running the tests yeah mpnt is your shortcut to
run the test correct and now you can see the
logging that says the client on this port is
talking to our reddest number three and it's
running this command get from a hash called
channels uh the key off hey it didn't see it
now it's setting a hash name channels key off
value one okay hey now it's adding something
to the Stream called app channels one and it
looks like the data is a string called first
event in this Channel with a type of Channel
Genesis so what we're seeing is the low-level
rdus commands that are involved in each of these
test scenarios okay and then I'll show you
one other thing um let's go to the messages
test and we can use the FIP or fit Alias or we can
type it. only but I like just adding an F the f
is a shortcut for focus focus on one test and now
when we run the tests uh for what was it messages
it'll still dump all the redus information but now
it's just focusing on one test and no matter how
far we scroll back we know that it's just one
test worth of um stuff oops let me just rerun
that there's one test and we can see
the entire transcript of the whole
test okay if we want to rerun it we press R to
rerun it with VI test and now we have another
transcript of that whole test so you see exactly
and only what this test is doing right exactly
are you getting uh music yes a little bit of
rock but it's quiet yes it's it's good uh for uh
concentrating on your words with a little bit of
yeah it's it's quite good yeah okay
so now basically when I create yeah
this this habit of focusing on one
test at a time is super powerful and
then when we're done with one test
we can switch the focus to another
test or we can tell it run the
whole thing by removing all the fs
um three skipped I'm just going
to I'm just going to press R to
tell it to rerun that's only running one
test I'm searching for fit ah we already
had one fit removing that one fit now
it's running all the tests in this file
so you basically enclose uh any test
portion in a fit uh block and this
block only the first that contains
fit is executed no um so tell me
how it works please you're close
you're close um the main the main
main uh accuracy problem in your
statement is the idea of a block um
it specifies a unit test this unit test asserts
that the client will not post messages or or the
the server will not allow messages to be posted
to a non-existent channel this logic is that whole
test so that's the main problem with what
you said when we focus on this test it runs
that test the smaller problem with what you
said is watch this if I focus on two tests it
runs two tests so it does not run the first
test that you focus on it runs all the focus
tests sense so let me try to summarize it is um
provided by v test and allows you to run a single
unit test but by um changing it uh adding the
fit that means you focus only on um uh one it
and it's the first uh unit test that you encounter
along the execution no it defines a unit test does
not run a unit test it defines a unit test fit
says run this test and Running Fit twice runs two
tests if we say fit four times it runs four
tests okay then I don't understand
the difference I don't understand the
differ does it makes sense now h no
what is the difference between fit and
it it is it. only it
only says only run this test but what it
actually does is it filters out any other
tests fit enables this test and disables
any other tests that don't have it okay
or they don't have fit so let's
look at the code that we have
if I if at line uh okay let's just stop here
at line 21 I have e dot only and also at line
35 I have it dot only or fit now if the test
at line 21 is executed then the other test
at line 35 is skied is that correct no okay
do you see the screen you see the terminal
yeah I do yes two tests did run two tests were
skipped two tests pass two tests skipped two tests
focused two tests executed yes two
tests skipped okay every test you
mark with a fit is executed any
test you do not Mark with a fit
is skipped now it's clear unless you remove all
the fits and then it executes all the uh and then
it runs all the tests that's clear now thank you
yeah I phrasing is confusing yeah I don't I I did
not understand is only uh the the meaning on
of only apply to it but now I understand how
it works it's it's genuinely confusing the word
doesn't the word doesn't mean what you think it
means okay if you understand
English like this Behavior says only do this
what does it mean to say this like yeah exactly
no but yeah runs runs them both you can um you
can do like describe dot only but I don't find it
useful This would run two
tests Maybe I'm
Wrong yeah I I know how it works in this
specific case that's enough yeah fair
enough yeah let's not worry about describe
that only um yeah fit fit is my friend I I
really I really get a lot of value out
of it um so that's why I wanted to show
you I was uh I was fighting this weekend with some
these tests and um we saw a case of this
failure um here I believe it was in this
test yeah
and I was getting ready to
um change this test to um
not use client. poost message because this is high
level but instead to use a low
level um thing like
this something like that you
post and and send and expect
these okay and I wanted wanted
you to um sorry I wanted you to
see this change because it might be
important for your replication tests
to know the difference between the
highlevel client and the low-level
client um I need to step away for
just a minute um just don't worry
okay meanwhile you can go look very quickly
at something called Super Test um or super
agent okay so you're saying that there is in the
test setup something called super
test. agent something like this
but you mentioned super agent so it's a bit tricky
I see is super test in the test server and then uh
it's used uh in test server line 167 on my hand
to super test. agent of app and then the agent
it's then used there in uh in the message tests
to like I see looks like you are composing a
a a chain of calls uh on this I knew that
you would totally understand this mode of
interacting with it because it's very Java likee
right yeah to have this chain um chaining pattern
yeah the um the the super agent is it has a um
it has a fluent API but all it does is make HTTP
requests it's very simple in that regard um okay
so if I look there uh 133 it basically it posts
uh in that channel it's that channel executes
a post the the payload is MSG is what it sends
the 135 expect is the content type that expects
and the second expect I'm not sure but maybe in
case something goes wrong it expects a 404 cuz
44 typically is denied this this is a this is
a this is a wrong expectation for this test okay
you're right it it it's expecting a 404 because
the place I pasted from was wanting a 404 okay
so now the question uh one more question is can
you add an expect to say 4 0 so beyond expecting
a given text can you also expect uh like a return
code like okay for instance 200 that everything
was okay this this is valid sure okay cool yeah
that's this this is it's it's a um I said it just
makes HTTP calls but you can see that it also is
helping you write your test by expecting the um
you can add these assertions to that that call
so it's really nice um and it's lowlevel so the
the other the other thing about it being lowlevel
is that it doesn't do things that the dread client
does and I wanted to point you to one particular
thing that it doesn't do which is adding this
oci the sorry the ocid is a um generated we
have something that automatically generates
message identifiers on the client side OC is
original client so ocid is the original client
side ID for the message and it's generated
with this thing automatically by The Dread
client and um that's not going
to happen in in the um lowlevel
post that this agent is doing so probably
what we need in this test is to say send a
message uh with ocid is this and
then
here include a different
ocid this might work this is the only addition I
should um perform to to have to to do a correct
call uh that's my hope we may we may need
to verify um exactly what the server is
receiving and so I might say loging equals
one rdus monitor equals one run the one test
and let's see if we get some useful output from
the server this is the dread server responding
to an HTTP request looks like it created
a channel but I'm looking for an HTTP um
log can can you search in in here with contrl f
uh here's what I was looking for
okay it might be more practical to
turn off the redus monitor use logging
and then be able to see without all the
reddis events um what HTTP calls the server is
getting here we're seeing some
um Json logs M we can format
those oops we can format those
by piping through um npm you know
pretty and now those same things that were Json
are now looking like this
yep it's a little bit more
useful I did not know P pretty um can I can I ask
you to search for the um original Channel ID that
you uh set in your code when you performed the P
this is right here that's this okay and you you
don't see can you scroll up a little bit okay stop
I I don't see the the channel ID logged anywhere
sorry the original Channel this
line this line here is the first
um you aren't seeing the channel creation but I'm
I'm betting it's here uh Channel created
News Channel created off Channel created
discussion uh
okay Channel created keep
going I wonder this this may be actually not the
posting of a message this may be the creation of
the channel chel so this this looks like it is the
creation of a channel and it succeeds okay yes and
then um this is the first place where I see the
oad just toward the the bottom you see I see a ooc
a post message hello word keep consuming please
greeting and oid MF that that's the first one
I I I I wanted to know um if when I
I do that type of um chained message
send and receive I can see the oid in
uh this um um output yeah if you have
logging enabled it should um show that to you
that's fine I I I think I will have no problem
it's I'd like to finish showing you the
transcript of of what's Happening Here
with with my commentary because the log doesn't
say what the semantics are um it tells you what
happens but it doesn't tell you how to understand
it so this line says we finished the post for
creating the channel this says we are um either
posting to a channel called oh this says we are
posting a request to listen this is a subscription
and the request is listen on these three channels
and what you'll what you'll notice is that there's
no response this is a response log that says we
finished that request this is a request log
saying we started this request and there's no
response I I see the the right arrow and the
left Arrow the the the left Arrow says this is
a response the right AR means this is a request
yeah yeah what what the implication here is that
the listen request starts and continues it'll
finish later yeah I totally see that it's a
synchronous so that's yeah this is our this is
our message real time message Channel then it
goes on to post um a message to this channel
keep going and like you pointed out there it
is it's got an oid it's got a Json string having
the content of the message the request succeeds
hey here's another one here is uh so the
first one had oci ID that was generated the
second one has an oci ID that we made
perfect there's the O ID that we made
now we have a confirmation that the thing
the client does and the thing that we did
manually with super test super agent they're
the same format of request that's a good
sign and there's the completion
of the event hey look at
this this log is telling us that the listen
request that we started and did not finish up
here has recognized the presence
of an event either this one or that
one and it has notified the client
that's listening that there is that event
and I believe this is our client side log saying
hey the server told us about this
new event there's the ooc ID so
we can see exactly which source event
triggered this client side notification
here's yet another event the server received
it this is the second lowlevel
event that we posted uh here 42
4321 42 4321 received by the server server post
message it finished that request successfully
y hey here's the client saying
hey there's 42 4321 I received
it this is a very good sign I'm
I'm really liking what I'm seeing
here um and skipping past some of these info
messages about State machines in The Connection
Manager um we come to another error or we come
to an error and um I'm trying to set it up so
that this does not happen yeah I don't I
don't want to spend your recording time
getting into all the details about this um
so I just want to to draw a line here in our
in our recording to say you can now
see a sequence of messages being
posted on the server side a sequence that
includes the notifications to a listening
client and not just one notification
but multiple notifications and if we
skip past um these errors that we're not being
distracted by yeah look post SL channel list
it's now complete the request has finished
I see I think this request finished because
the client um disconnected at the end of the
test the um o sorry at the end of the test
there's a tear down uh that's not obvious
but there is a tear down that says after
after everything runs clean things up and I
think this is what triggers that disconnect
thus the server side logs the result of that
request that was long running uh long 787
milliseconds not a 20 millisecond
request does that make
sense it it it does I think I have a
feeling why that happened uh but yeah we don't
care for the moment it's just a tear down problem
I guess and uh I think you're talking about the
errors yeah yeah I think I do understand how
um the the sequence of sending receiving can be
observed in logs so basically I will be able to
uh perform tests formulate hypothesis on how
a message should be sent and received and of
course if I find some um tear down error
either I'll ignore it or I'll I'll find
a graceful way to uh you know handle the
the closeup um uh maybe waiting sometime
until it's closed so I I think uh I
I understand how to use the log to uh
confirm like the the theory behind the tests
good excellent that that's the that's the
main point um and you're right you're right
that these um that these errors are just tear
down problems um I want to fix them but um
fundamentally they're just they're just um
clean up sequence quencing problems let me ask
you one last thing um in um in the duplication
test we will have two servers uh each one with uh
um a a proper uh client that does the replication
now when I see all the messages logged here uh
are these messages uh just all the messages sent
on radish or that's yeah because if I look at
radish output I probably see all the messages
that are passing through Ries and I'm not sure
if these logs are specific for one server or
are for everything iess I guess it's for one
server just well you your guess is sensible
it's the same guess I made and it's wrong um what
we see here is that redis has received a command
select one and then another command info Etc and
these are these are all on server one server the
the redus database number one okay and then and
then what happens is is when there's a second
client reddis database number two
now I see receives these things so
the the redis monitor output shows all
commands received by the reddis server
okay it Flags each one with the
database number that's involved
and now uh one more thing about the logging so
now we are running the test we just logging but
when you say logging basically this information is
transferred to redis which is the one printing out
all these logs is that correct uh no it's um
again a good guess but um it's it's not quite
accurate let me tell you two things number one
loging equals 1 is um it's a signal to the dread
server code okay redus monitor is a signal to the
testing code and I'll show you how that works Rus
monitor says if that environment variable is
set it makes a new redus connection you can
see it's connecting to database 9 which is um
just to make it separate from everything else
yeah and then um it tells you if there's
no monitor it tells you hey if you want to
monitor do this and then the other thing it
does is when um when it starts up the tests
before all the tests run one time it says
monitor when there's an event from redis
um do the logging this this incantation right
here is triggering the reddis command called
monitor so if you search for reddis
monitor you see exactly how that works
yep I'm searching uh and there it
is it's a debugging command that
streams back every command processed by the redus
server perfect so you say Monitor and
it starts telling you all the commands
that it got um I'll show you one other thing
which is that monitor is not cheap it degrades
performance by 40% whoa yeah of course it's so
fast in sending just message that if you start
writing out all of the [ __ ] yeah I get it
yeah yeah and um I should tell you one other
thing I'm just trying to remember what it is
um so you have the reddest monitor
it it shows what's going on um in terms
of commands that are sent to the reddest
server the thing that's that you
will not see um even though you
would expect it or you would hope for
it is um um when a message is added to
a channel this is a redis streams data
structure using the Reds X add command
it's adding a message to this channel
name to this reddis stream name it's
adding that message that has these details
and what's surprising about the monitor is
it shows the message being added but it does
not show anyone being notified even though
it notifies people so we saw in the log
that there is a notification that arrives
on the server H sorry on the client the guy
who's listening receives the event there it
is it's being logged by um logged by the
client object and you don't see anything
in the redus monitor that says we're
notifying somebody the redus monitor
only shows input commands to Reds I get it
that's why we need the logging to show what
the participants are actually getting yeah
exactly and um if we if we go back here to that
listen command I'll do a search for listen uh post
listen um probably we'll see a rdus command that
says um that shows how listening is done
and what it's saying is it makes X group
create which is um um consumer group okay if
you've ever used Kafka this consumer group
ID it's this very same idea it makes the
consumer group and then it looks like it
is deleting that consumer group right
away which I don't think is right but
um uh interesting we we don't see the
notification but we see the commands that are used
um oh it this is the destroy this is just deleting
a consumer so these are the
commands relating to a listen
on that um this is for the channel channels
stream okay we keep going down stop stop stop
for a second please here I want to ask you a
quick question so if we look at your um sorry at
your console we see a first message sent and then
in in response red is uh uh basically creates a
group then deletes a consumer and then send some
information to the groups without that consumer
and then it destroys that X group that I guess was
created just for uh the specific purpose does this
make sense I don't know all the details um these
are handled by a library sometimes I look at that
library and I learn all the details again but um
the the short version of all this is in order to
listen freshly to the Channel's stream
it does this stuff and um then this is
the really interesting one it says read up to 10
messages from that stream okay this is the real
thing all this other stuff is just set up okay
I I think this says read the events from the
stream I think complete I I think I have really
enough information to to handle the understanding
writing and understanding both what happens
on redish and especially what happens from
the the participants server and client got it
yeah yeah yeah um doesn't do any any better
if I understand better red is now it's more
about using it but so just to just to come
back to the point that I was making here we see
what the commands are their Center redus and we
don't see the events that come back from that xre
command until we find that they've been notified
somewhere okay yes so I would stop the recording
now I assume there is no more information